TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
《天國大魔境》 （推動發車）
No more human experiments!
停止人體實驗
Cutting off a leg just for your experiments
為了實驗把別人的腿砍了
isn't something a human would do!
你還算是人嗎？
FREE THE PATIENTS STOP HUMAN EXPERIMENTS
（讓病人重獲自由） （停止人體實驗）
-No more human experiments! -That's right!
-停止人體實驗 -沒錯
That bastard! Well, let's do it right here!
那個渾球，我們從這裡動手吧
Miss Mizuhashi!
水橋小姐
That's foul! Violence is wrong!
太惡劣了，不該使用暴力
-Violence is wrong! -No violence!
-不該使用暴力 -拒絕暴力
One rock, and all hell breaks loose.
一顆石頭就引發了群情激奮
They are just a group of revelers with no beliefs.
他們只是一群缺乏信念的烏合之眾
No, they are acting strangely today.
不，他們今天的舉動不太對勁
I thought they'd be emotional for a while.
我以為他們會再持續一陣子
I can't believe they left after just one rock.
我不敢相信一顆石頭就能讓他們鳥獸散
It's like it served another purpose.
他們彷彿另有目的
Yeah. They're going to use this rock as an excuse to do anything.
對呀，他們會利用這顆石頭 做為藉口為所欲為
They may demand something.
他們或許會要求些什麼
Even though they threw the stone first?
即便石頭是他們先動手丟的？
They're the ones who think "what we do is an expression of what we do
他們這種人總是覺得 「我們這麼做是在仗義直言
and what others do is an attack."
別人這麼做就是在攻擊」
-Leader! -Are you okay?
-領導人 -妳沒事吧？
Excuse me.
不好意思
Let me through!
請讓我過去
I was able to confirm from the guard on watch.
我和負責看守的警衛確認過了
He said the monsters in the basement are really dead.
他說地下室的怪物真的都死了
We must not miss this chance!
我們絕不能錯過這個機會
Listen up, everyone.
聽好了，各位
The leader
我們的領導
is dead.
過世了
The leader was subjected to inhumane experimentation
首領遭到非人對待，成了實驗品
and had her leg cut off.
她的腿被砍斷了
And yet, she still stood up to save the test subject
但她仍然挺身而出，為了救出
held captive by the Immortal Order.
被不滅教團囚禁的受試者
Defeat the enemies of the leader!
打敗與領袖為敵的人！
Grab your weapons!
拿起你們的武器
Hey, hey.
怎麼搞的？
Doctor!
醫生
Doctor, my prosthetic hand is making strange noises.
醫生，我的義肢手會發出奇怪的聲音
You can ask someone to spray it with oil or silicone spray.
你叫人幫你在這個地方上一些油
Just this one place is enough.
或噴一些矽膠噴霧就可以了
Doctor, this child doesn't know how to control the strength.
醫生，這個孩子不知道該如何控制力道
Can't you do something about it?
可以請你幫忙一下嗎？
You get used to it. You just have to get used to it.
會漸漸習慣的，就是得花時間適應它
-Doctor! -Dr. Usami.
-醫生 -宇佐美醫生
Let's go.
我們走吧
Is it okay?
這樣好嗎？
There is no end to it.
他們總是沒完沒了
In here.
到了
I want you to see if you can make her die using the same method you used
我想要你們看看是否能用 殺死地下室怪物的方法
to kill the monsters in the basement.
殺死她
This is…
這是…
the curtain that Mizuhashi mentioned.
水橋提過的簾子
Th-They say
他們說…
it's the cornerstone of their patients' treatment.
這是他們治療病人的基石
Why don't you just turn off the machines if you want to let her die?
如果你想要她死的話 為何不乾脆關掉機器就好？
If I did, she'll become a monster like the ones in the basement.
這麼做的話 就會讓她變得跟地下室那群怪物一樣
She's going to become a Man-eater?
她會變成食人者？
Are Man-eaters human?
食人者是人類？
If you ask me if they are human, they are a little different.
如果你問我牠們是否是人類 我會說兩者有些不一樣
They are former humans who died from a disease
他們本來是人類，後來死於
that turns them into monsters.
這個讓他們變成怪物的疾病
The facilities here were created to prolong her life as a human
在她得了這個病之後 我們便在這裡打造出
after she developed that disease.
這些設備以維持她的人類壽命
To slow the progression,
為了減緩惡化
you have to cut out the part of the body that is diseased.
就得切割掉發病的身體部位
Still, once it develops,
但是，一旦得了這種病
you will eventually relapse.
患者終究會復發
And the diseased parts will need to be removed again.
受到影響的部位又得再割除一次
If the body can no longer function, it is supplemented by the machines.
如果該身體部位的功能盡失之後 就會以機器來取代
I've been doing all this for a long time.
我這麼做已經很長一段時間了
But her body has reached its limit.
但她的身體已到達了極限
She may be able to die as a human
透過你殺死地下室怪物的那種方法
with the method you used to kill the monsters in the basement.
或許能讓她以人類的樣貌死去
It's our only hope.
這是我們唯一的希望
I can do it.
我辦得到
You can?
你可以？
But what does she want?
但她想要的是什麼呢？
She can communicate through that tablet.
她可以透過平板溝通
And she can hear us.
她聽得見我們
I WANT
（我想要）
I WANT TO SEE
（我想要看）
THE SKY ONE LAST TIME
（天空最後一眼）
Can she be taken outside?
可以帶她去外面嗎？
She can't be removed from the machines.
她不能離開這些機器
From here.
從這裡
To here.
到這裡
It's only this far.
只有這點距離
We'll help you.
我們會協助你
If you can't do that, I won't do it either.
如果你辦不到的話，我就不會下手
Good. That's right. Softly.
很好，這樣可以，輕一點
Softly.
輕一點
-Place that close to her. -Got it.
-放在靠近她的地方 -好
Put this by her side as well.
把這個也放在她旁邊
Looks like I need to extend this.
看來我得用延長線
I need you to get into her line of sight
妳需要進入她的視線範圍內
because she won't be able to hear anything for a moment.
因為她會有一段時間聽不到
THAT HURTS! YOU IDIOT!
（很痛，你白癡啊）
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉，對不起
Calling me an idiot…
說我白癡…
All the stairs are blocked!
所有的樓梯口都堵住了
-Go around! -Let's go!
-繞一圈吧 -走吧
Geez.
天啊
The time has come.
這個時刻終於來臨了
Hey!
喂
The gen--
你…
It's retribution for killing Miss Mizuhashi!
這是為了懲罰你們殺了水橋小姐
Yeah!
對
Gotta do what must be done!
該做的事就得做
Rush in through here!
從這裡衝進去
This is bad!
糟糕了
The Whiteshirts just showed up, armed to the teeth!
白衣人突然出現了，還全副武裝
Damn. I thought they weren't going to be violent.
可惡，我還以為他們不會使用暴力
Everyone move upstairs! Those who can move, assist the wounded!
全員往樓上移動 行動便利的人請協助傷患
Hey, it's kind of noisy.
吵鬧聲有點大
Just leave it alone.
別管他們
That room's a decoy! Watch out for it!
那個房間是個誘餌，要特別注意
It might've been easier just to let her turn into a monster.
讓她變成怪物可能還比較輕鬆
I've made her suffer for a long time.
我已經讓她受苦很久了
Maru, Maru. Look at this.
小丸，小丸，你看
Usami, look at this.
宇佐美，你看這個
THANK YOU FOR LETTING ME DIE AS A HUMAN
（謝謝你讓我以人類的樣貌死去）
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME YOUR EYE
（謝謝你給了我你的眼睛）
THANK YOU
（謝謝）
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING
（謝謝你為我所做的一切）
I LOVE YOU
（我愛你）
Is everyone here? Anyone else hurt?
大家都在這裡了嗎？有人受傷嗎？
Naito was the first to jump out at them.
內藤是第一個跳出來面對他們的人
Damn it.
該死
Doctor!
醫生
You're unharmed.
你安然無恙
They said something about Mizuhashi's death and broke in.
他們說水橋死了，而且還闖了進來
We need to regain power immediately.
我們需要立刻拿回主控權
Or Miss Hoshio will…
不然星尾小姐…
She's already dead.
她已經死了
Don't tell me they…
難道是他們…
No, she died a natural death.
不是，她是自然死亡
There should be a settlement here.
那裡應該有個可以落腳的地方
Can you make it there before the sun goes down?
你們有辦法在日落之前抵達那裡嗎？
What about you, Doctor? You're not coming with us?
那你呢，醫生？你不跟我們一起走嗎？
I'll follow you with the guards after giving her a burial.
替她安葬之後，我會和保鏢一起趕上你們
Go first without me.
你們先走吧
Why do we have to get chased out of where we live?
我們為什麼要被趕出自己的地盤啊？
Because I killed monsters in the basement.
是因為我殺了地下室的怪物
That's why this happened, isn't it?
所以才會變成這樣，對吧？
-Maru-- -It doesn't matter.
-小丸 -無所謂
Almost all the facilities in that building were made for her.
那棟大樓裡所有的設備 幾乎都是為她打造的
They're no longer necessary.
已經沒有存在的必要了
There are still wounded.
但仍然有傷患
There's a lot of people who want to be treated by you.
有很多人都想接受你的治療
We were originally two people living together.
一開始就只有我們兩人相依為命
An injured man wandered into the house.
有個受傷的人誤入了這棟房子
I made him a prosthetic hand on a whim.
我一時興起就替他做了義肢手
Before I knew it, more and more people arrived.
不知不覺間，來了愈來愈多的人
Oh, yes.
對了
It makes her happy when I make things.
每當我做出新的成品時 總是會讓她很開心
That's why I made it.
所以我才會這麼做
That's why.
就只是這樣
I am not a doctor.
我不是醫生
Wonderful.
太棒了
I've got the future in my hands.
未來在我的手中了
With this many power generators,
有了這麼多發電機
we can build a city here.
我們就能在這裡打造出一座城市
A new culture
在這個破敗的世界
in this broken world!
建立起一個新的文化
All we need now is one order and leadership.
我們現在只需要一個唯一秩序和領導者
A nation.
一個國家
This is the end of childish factions.
幼稚的派系鬥爭該結束了
We start here!
就從這裡開始吧
Excuse me, everyone.
各位，不好意思
Sorry to bother you at this difficult time.
不好意思在這麼混亂的時刻打擾各位
Have you seen these two?
你們見過這兩個人嗎？
This one is a doctor.
這位是一名醫生
I don't know.
我不認識
This forehead scar is something I'd remember if I saw it once.
額頭上的疤我見過的話，應該就忘不了
In the three years I've been with the Doctor, I've never seen him.
我跟在醫生身邊這三年間，從沒見過他
This good-looking guy? Isn't this Dr. Inazaki?
這個帥哥不就是稻崎醫生嗎？
What?
什麼？
Oh, yes! This is Dr. Inazaki.
對耶，他是稻崎醫生
It was long before the Whiteshirts started messing around.
他早在白衣人開始作亂之前就在這裡了
So, about two years ago.
大約是兩年前吧
One day, without saying a word,
某一天，他突然
he was just gone.
就不告而別了
He had surgical knowledge and was studying Dr. Usami's technique.
他本來就有醫學知識 然後又跟著宇佐美醫生學習他的技術
He said he's not going to let anyone else die.
他說他不會再讓任何人斷送性命了
He was an enthusiastic man.
他是一個充滿熱忱的人
It's Robin.
是露敏
It's definitely Robin. I knew you were alive.
絕對是露敏，我就知道你還活著
I want to see you!
我想見你
I have to!
我一定要見到你
Sis.
姊
Are you going to guard Usami?
妳打算當宇佐美的保鏢嗎？
Oh.
這個喔
Oh, it's just the way things went.
不知不覺就變成這樣了
-You also want to know about Robin. -Wha--
-妳也想詢問有關露敏的事 -什麼？
Of course I'll ask about him.
那是當然的囉
Okay, okay.
好啦，好啦
Isn't Usami done yet?
宇佐美還沒結束嗎？
What--
什麼？
Damn it.
該死
Maru?
小丸？
I'm the total opposite of Usami and Robin.
我與宇佐美和露敏完全相反
My hands…
我的手…
bring only death!
只會帶來死亡
Idiot!
白癡
Don't say that.
別說這種話
Don't you dare say that.
不准你說這種話
When you kill Man-eaters,
當你殺了食人者之後
people won't be eaten anymore.
再也不會有人類被吃掉
You're saving everyone's life!
這就是在救大家一命
THEIR CHOICES
（他們的選擇）
I wonder where I am.
我在哪裡啊？
It's dark.
好黑
Somehow
不知為何
I hate it.
我很討厭這樣
It's scary.
好可怕
You came!
你來了
Well, then.
那麼…
It's not scary.
我就不怕了
Why are you grinning all by yourself?
妳怎麼一個人在傻笑？
I don't know.
我也不知道
I had a dream that made me happy.
我做了一個令人開心的美夢
What kind?
什麼夢？
I don't remember anymore.
我什麼都不記得了